Guide to the Joseph Henry Steele Papers, 1927-1972
Department of Special Collections
Joseph Henry Steele Papers,
1927-1972
Special Collections M0239
Steele, Joseph Henry.
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Partially restricted: for more information contact the Manuscripts Librarian.
Provenance
Gift of Joseph Henry Steele, 1974.
Scope and Content
The collection is comprised of correspondence between J.H. Steele and various people re: Steele's biography of Ingrid Bergman. One box contains correspondence between J.H. Steele and Ingrid Bergman only. In addition to the correspondence, there are a few legal documents and some financial papers magazines.
Container List
- BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE RE: BOOK ON BERGMAN (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. 1958, Feb. 10.Los Angeles, Ca. JHS to Constance Smith., TL 1p.
  - 2. 1958, Feb. 24.Los Angeles, Ca. JHS to [Constance] Smith., TL 2pp.
  - 3. 1958, Feb. 25.[Los Angeles, Ca.]. JHS to [Constance] Smith., TL 2pp.
  - 4. 1958, Mar. 3.[Los Angeles, Ca.]. JHS to Walter _____(?), TL 2pp.
  - 5. 1961, March 10.New York, N.Y. Constance Smith to JHS., TLS 1p.
  - 6. 1961, March 13.[Los Angeles, Ca.]. JHS to Connie [Constance] Smith. TL. 1p. A Statement of Facts in re Modern Screen by JHS, attached.
  - 7. 1961, April 27.New York, N.Y. Harriet F. Pilpel (of Greenbaum, Wolff & Ernst) to Constance Smith, JHS and Ken Rawson., TLS 3pp.
  - 8. 1961, Oct. 2.New York, N.Y. Julia Perles (of Greenbaum, Wolff & Ernst) to JHS., TLS 1p.
  - 9. 1961, Oct. 6.Same as # 8.
  - 10. 1961, Nov. 2.Same as # 8.
  - 11. 1965, (?).The Hague, Holland. G.F. Kaal to Heer A. Gans, in Dutch., TLS 1p.
  - 12. 1966(?).The Hague, Holland. C. Th. Vogelesang (of Zuid-Hollandsche Vitgevers Maatschappij) to Heer A. Gans., TLS 1p.
  - 13. 1967 (?).Same as # 12.
  - 14. 1967, Feb. 24.New York, N.Y. Patricia Schartle (of McIntosh and Otis, Inc.) to JHS., TLS 1p.
- FAN MAIL - ALS & TLS's - 1959-1963, 1965-1966. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- MISCELLANEOUS CORRESPONDENCE (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1. 1932, Dec. 2.New York, Clare Boothe Brokaw, Managing Editor - Vanity Fair, to JHS re: publication of the book Sister Aimes., TLS 1p.
  - 2. 1943, May 21.Hollywood, Ca. Ruth Waterbury (of Movieland) to J[HS] re: Bergman book., TLS 1p.
  - 3. 1948, June 11.Los Angeles, Ca. Charles Boyer to JHS re: script Deadlock., TLS 1p.
  - 4. 1950, Mar. 7.New York, N.Y. Princess Barbara Troubetzkoi to J[HS]., TLS 1p.
  - 5. 1959, May 6.Los Angeles, Ca. William H. Powell to J[HS]., ANS 1p.
  - 6. 1959, July 1.Los Angeles, Ca. Guy Endore to JHS., ALS 1p.
  - 7. 1962, Oct. 12.Beverly Hills, Ca. Dick Irving Hyland to JHS re: book All the Questions a Cop Would Ask., TNS 1p.
  - 8. 1967, June 1.[Stanford, Ca.]. Ralph W. Hansen, Manuscripts Librarian, to Mr. & Mrs. Richard K. Mohler., TL. 1p.
  - 9. 1968, Jan. 15.NP. Bob _____(?) to J[HS] and Beatrice [Steele]., ALS.
  - 10. ND.Los Angeles, Ca. H.H. Chou, Asst. Prof., Univ. of Ca., L.A., to To Whom It May Concern., TNS 1p.
  - 11. ND.NP. Dad [JHS?] to Olivia and Dick., TNS 1p.
- LEGAL PAPERS (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1. Last Will and Testament: Joseph Henry Steele and Beatrice Salvador Steele, Addendum to Will.
  - 2. JHS and David McKay Co., Inc., May 9, 1958.
  - 3. JHS and Constance Smith Associates, June 25, 1959.
  - 4. JHS and Almquist & Wiksell/Gebers Forlag AB, Aug. 11, 1959.
  - 5. JHS and Alfred Scherz Verlag, Aug. 14, (two copies).
  - 6. JHS and Carit Andersen's Forlag, Oct. 14, 1959.
  - 7. JHS and John Griegs Forlag, Oct. 29, 1959.
  - 8. JHS nad Zuid-Hollandsche Vitgevers Maatschappij, March 15, 1960.
  - 9. JHS and Plaza & Janés, Nov. 17, 1960.
  - 10. JHS and Dell Publishing Co., Nov. 1961.
  - 11. Certificate of Charter Membership in the Writer's Guild of America, JHS, Aug. 25, 1954.
  - 12. Certificate from Hollywood Museum Associates acknowledging receipt of gifts from JHS. Mar. 26, 1964.
    [UNK]
  - 13. Application for Registration of a Claim to Renewal Copyright - blank form.
- FINANCIAL PAPERS RE: royalties on book from: Barclays Bank Limited; A.M. Heath & Co., Ltd.; Plaza & Janés, S.A.; Manufacturers Hanover Trust Co.; Chemical Bank New York Trust Co.; McIntosh and Otis, Inc.; David McKay Co., Inc Almquist & Wiksell/Gebers. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Box 1, Folder 6)
- MISCELLANEOUS (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1. Map of Paris - 1927
  - 2. Typescript: A Little Matter over Mind by Joseph H. Steele.
  - 3. Foreign currency - one note, 100,000 mark.
  - 4. Inscription on matting of photo portrait of David O. Selznick - written by Selznick to J[HS]. 1943, Nov.
  - 5. Program - Agua Caliente Jockey Club, 1931.
  - 6. Two tape recordings: interview with Ingrid Bergman - transatlantic to Paris.
  - 7. Key and key chain - JHS.
- MAGAZINES (Box 2)
  - 1. Allers Magazine, Oct. 8, 1972.
  - 2. Life Magazine, Vol. 33, No. 9, 1952, Sept. 1.
  - 3. Life Magazine, Vol. 53, No. 25, 1962, Dec. 1.
  - 4. Look Magazine, Vol. 16, No. 3, 1962, Jan. 29.
  - 5. Look Magazine, Vol. 16, No. 4, 1962, Feb. 12.
  - 6. Novella Magazine, 1958, April 13.
  - 7. Novella Magazine, 1958, April 20.
  - 8. Novella Magazine, 1958, April 27.
  - 9. Novella Magazine, 1958, May 4.
  - 10. Pleasure Magazine, Vol. 1, 1957, May.
- BOUND MAGAZINES, THREE VOLUMES
  - 1. Good Housekeeping, Vol. 149, No. 1, July 1959. (Box 2, Volume 1)
  - 2. Svensk Damtidning, Aug. 13, 1959(Swedish)
  - 3. Svensk Damtidning, Sept. 24, 1959(Swedish)
  - 4. Svensk Damtidning, Nov. 26, 1959(Swedish)
  - 5. Svensk Damtidning, Sept. 10, 1959(Swedish)
  - 6. Svensk Damtidning, Nov. 3, 1959(Swedish)
  - 1. L'Europeo, July 5, 1959(Italian) (Box 2, Volume 2)
  - 2. Woman, Vol. 45, No. 1170, Nov. 14, 1959
  - 3. Woman, Vol. 45, No. 1169, Nov. 7, 1959
  - 1. American Weekly, Los Angeles Examiner, Sept. 14, 1952 (Box 2, Volume 3)
  - 2. American Weekly, Los Angeles Examiner, Sept. 21, 1952
  - 3. Quick Magazine, April 30, 1960(German)
  - 4. Quick Magazine, May 7, 1960(German)
  - 5. Quick Magazine, May 14, 1960(German)
  - 6. Quick Magazine, May 21, 1960(German)
  - 7. Quick Magazine, May 28, 1960(German)
  - 8. Quick Magazine, June 11, 1960(German)
- SCRAPBOOKS, TWO VOLUMES
  - Re: Ingrid Bergman, 1942-1951, 1955, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Volume 1)
  - Re: Ingrid Bergman and Steele's biography of Bergman, 1956-1960 (Box 2, Volume 2)
    long term loan to J.H. [UNK]
- BERGMAN, INGRID CORRESPONDENCE. One large manila envelopes sealed until Miss Bergman's death. (in safe). (Box 3)
  Restricted
  (The other 3 are on long term loan to J.H. Steele)
Items on Loan
Steele, J.H. Long term loan - out
May 18, 1976
On this date Mr. Joseph Henry Steele Picked up the following materials from his collections donated to the Stanford University Libraries (M-167 and M-239), Manuscripts Division, Department of Special Collections:
M 239
3 envelopes from sealed container
Box 2 2 scrapbook
Box 1 Fld. 4 itemm 12: Hollywood Museum certificate
Received by: [signature: Joseph Henry Steele]
Joseph Henry Steele
Authorized by: [signature: J. Palmer]
Patricia J. Palmer, Manuscripts Librarian
Witnessed by: [UNK] [UNK]